好  这是他的尿布袋
Ok. Here's his diaper bag,
跟他的眨眼先生  还有...
and his uh, Mr. Winky, and...
他
him.
-一切都还好吗  -好  很好
- So how did everything go? - Oh, great. Great.
发生了一起喷射性呕吐事件
There was a projectile, throwing up incident,
但是他挑起的
but he started it.
-我们得走了  -好
- Well, we've gotta go. - Ok.
对了  我有个消息  是我们俩的
Oh, right. Um, I've got some news. It's about us.
-你跟我  -不  是苏珊跟我
- Oh, you and me? - Uh, no, Susan and me.
另一个"我们"
The other us.
好吧
Ok.
我们要结婚了
We're uh, we're getting married.
就像"现在宣布你们结为妻妻"那样正式吗
As in, "I now pronounce you wife and wife" married?
我们欢迎你来
Anyway, we'd like you to come,
但你不想来的话  我们也完全了解
but we totally understand if you don't want to.
我为什么会不想去
Why wouldn't I want to come?
我第一次结婚时就很开心
I had fun at the first wedding.
听着  我想也许...
Look, I just thought that...
不  我难道不该替你们高兴吗
No no no, I mean, hey, why shouldn't I be happy for you?
如果我不能分享你的快乐  那我算什么呢
What would it say about me if I couldn't revel in your joy?
我为你感到高兴  相信我
I'm revelling, baby, believe me!
你的手指被椅子夹住了吗
Is your finger caught in that chair?
要我们走吗
Want us to go?
真厉害  你真要上电视了
This is so cool. You're actually gonna be on television.
我知道  我昨晚真正意识到
I know. It really hit me last night.
我要出演《我们的日子》了
I'm gonna be on Days of our Lives.
然后我开始想我们的事
And then I started thinkin' about all of us,
我发现这正是"我们的日子"
and how these are the days of our lives..
-太好了  -怎么了
- Yes! - What?
承办卡罗尔跟苏珊的酒席的人
Carol and Susan's caterer
这周末骑登山车出了车祸
had a mountain bike accident this weekend,
全身都上了石膏
and she's in a full body cast.
太好了
Yes!
他们要我接手  这太好了
They want me to do it, which is really cool,
我从来没承办过酒席
seeing as I've never catered before,
现在又很缺钱  你没问题吧
and I really need the money, and this isn't a problem for you, is it?
-有什么关系吗  -你真善解人意  谢谢
- Would it matter? - Oh, you are so great! Thank you!
-你真的不去吗  -我真的不去
- Are you really not going? - I am really not going.
我不懂  她们已经同居了 为什么还要结婚
I don't get it. They already live together, why do they need to get married?
因为他们相爱
Because they love each other,
她们想跟亲朋好友一起庆祝这份爱
and they wanna celebrate that love with the people that are close with them.
这也勉强算一个理由
If you wanna call that a reason.
*谁是客厅里最痛苦的人*
*Who's the bitterest man in the living room*
*客厅里最痛苦的男人*
*the bitterest man in the living room*
你好  邻居
Hi, neighbor.
罗斯  我以为你不在意了
Ross, I thought you were over this.
这和在不在意没关系
Look, that has nothing to do with this, ok?
她是我前妻
She's my ex-wife.
她要是嫁了个男的  那我不去就理所当然了
If she were marrying a guy, none of you'd expect me to be there.
她要是嫁了个男的
Hey, if she were marrying a guy,
岂不是史上最不厚道的同志了
she'd be like the worst lesbian ever.
我错过了吗  我错过了吗
Did I miss it? Did I miss it?
还没  这家伙自杀后就该我出场了
No, I'm on right after this guy shoots himself.
-她很养眼  -对  她人也很好
- Whoa, she's pretty.- Yeah, and she's really nice too.
她教我怎么样在镜头前演戏
She taught me all about you know, how to work with the cameras,
还教我闻屁味表演法
and smell-the-fart acting.
-对不起  -什么闻屁味表演法
- I'm sorry, what? - What? Smell-the-fart acting.
在短时间内要记那么多台词
It's like, you got so many lines to learn so fast,
有时候你需要时间想下一句
that sometimes you need a minute to remember your next one.
所以当你酝酿下句的时候
So while you're thinkin' of it,
你停顿一下  表情装得非常的凝重
you take this big pause where you look all intense,
就像这样
you know, like this.
这样啊
Ok.
轮到我了  我的戏
There's my scene, there's my scene.
-华莱士女士  -你好
- Mrs. Wallace, - Yes.
我是德雷克·拉莫雷医生
I'm Dr. Drake Ramoray,
令妹的神经外科医生
your sister's neurosurgeon.
告诉我  她会不会好起来
Tell me, is she gonna be all right?
恐怕令妹的病情比我们预想的还糟
I'm afraid the situation is much more dier than we expected.
令妹得的病是...
Your sister is suffering from a..
颅下血肿
subcranial hematoma.
或许我们可以边喝咖啡边聊病情
Perhaps we can discuss this further over coffee.
-帅  -很好  -演得太好了
- Nice! - That's great!  - Excellent!
有那么一会  我还真以为你闻到了什么味道
For a minute there I thought you were actually tryin' to smell something.
再来一次  演得太棒了  再来一次
Do it. That is so good! Do it again!
好
All right, all right.
"该死  布雷弗曼  就在那张图表上"
"Damn it, Braverman, it's right there on the chart!"
演得很好  好了  我要去上班了
That's great. All right, I gotta get to work,
我有根大恐龙骨头要检查
I got a big dinosaur bone to inspect.
-不  那是我才对  -对  是你
- No no, that's me. - Oh, right.
-你好  -谢了  我没办法...
- Oh, hello. - Oh, thanks. I couldn't uh...
-你还好吧  -不好
- Is everything ok? - Um, no, huh-uh.
今天我有个客人死在按摩床上
One of my clients died on the massage table today.
天啊
Oh my god.
你的客人也有点放松过头了吧
That's a little more relaxed than you want them to get.
对  她已经八十二岁了
Yeah, um, she was 82 years old.
她叫艾德曼太太
Her name was um, Mrs. Adelman.
-亲爱的  -对  感觉怪怪的
- Oh, honey. - Yeah, it's just so strange.
她早上醒来时说不定在想
I mean, she probably woke up today and thought,
"我去吃点早餐"
"ok, I'll have some breakfast,
"再去散会儿步  然后去做个小按摩"
and then I'll take a little walk, and then I'll have my massage."
她怎么会料到上帝在想
Little did she know God was thinking,
"好  但到此为止"
"Ok, but that's it."
最诡异的事情是
Oh, but the weirdest thing was,
她死的时候我正在清她的灵气
ok, I was cleansing her aura when that happened,
当她的灵魂离开身体的时候
and when the spirit left her body,
我觉得它没走远
I don't think it went very far.
什么意思
What do you mean?
我想它上了我的身
I think it went into me.
太难抉择了  我决定不了选羔羊还是鸭子
God, this is so hard. I can't decide between lamb or duck.
当然了  羔羊比较恐怖
Well, of course, lambs are scarier.
不然那部电影就叫《沉默的鸭子》了
Otherwise the movie would've been called Silence of the Ducks.
好了  谁点了什么
Ok, who ordered what?
我一定点了喝了一半的卡布奇诺
Oh, I believe I had the half-drunk cappuccino
上面还得留有唇印
with the lipstick on the rim.
对  这杯有烟蒂的是无咖啡因的吗
Yes, and this with the cigarette butt in it, is that decaf?
天呐
Oh god.
真不敢相信  你妈来会把你吓成这样
I can't believe you're so uptight about your mom comin'.
我知道  只是这是她第一次来
I know, but it's just it's the first time,
我不想她觉得
and I just don't want her to think that
我没嫁给巴瑞  我的生活就完全是垃圾
because I didn't marry Barry, that my life is total crap, you know?
说到垃圾
Talk about crap.
你不妨去听听史黛拉·倪德曼讲述
Try listening to Stella Niedman tell the story
她和罗德·斯泰格尔的老掉牙的故事
of her and Rod Steiger for the hundredth time.
菲比  你觉得她会跟我们在一起待多久
Uh, Pheebs, how long do you think this lady'll be with us?
不知道  老太太肯定还有什么未了的心愿
I don't know. I mean, she obviously has some kind of unfinished business.
坐端正
Sit up!
-乖女儿  -妈
- There she is. - Mom!
亲爱的
Sweetie!
这就是你上班的地方吗
So this is where you work?
真不错
Oh, it's wonderful!
这是客厅吗  还是餐厅  谁看得出来
Is it a living room? Is it a restaurant? Who can tell?
我想这就是乐趣所在吧
But I guess that's the fun.
差不多啦  来  见见我的朋友
Pretty much. Here, meet my frends.
摩妮卡  你美极了
Monica! You look gorgeous!
莫妮卡  上回见你时
Mon. Last time I saw you,
你不是在吃  就是在被吃
it was eat or be eaten.
他是乔伊
This is Joey,
她是菲比  他是钱德勒  你记得罗斯吧
this is Phoebe, and this is Chandler, and you remember Ross.
-你好  罗斯  -你好  格林太太
- Oh hello, Ross. - Hi, Mrs. Green.
那...
So,
你们觉得我系着围裙做大事的女儿怎么样
what do you think of my daughter in the apron with the big job?
妈
Oh Mom!
没有你来倒咖啡  大家都休想喝到东西
If you didn't pour the coffee, no one would have anything to drink.
相信我  有时候真是这样
Believe me, sometimes that happens.
太令人兴奋了  我从来没工作过
This is just so exciting. You know, I never worked.
我直接从我爸家搬到女生联谊会
I went straight from my father's house
再搬到我老公家
to the sorority house to my husband's house.
我真是为你骄傲
I am just so proud of you.
-真的吗  -是的
- Really? - Yes.
我知道你让我想起谁了
I know who it is you remind me of.
伊芙琳·德玛  当然是她做那烂整容手术前
Evelyn Dermer. 'Course, that's before she got the lousy face lift.
现在她像苏比·赛尔斯了
Now she looks like Soupy Sales.
菲比  伊芙琳·德玛是谁
Pheebs, who's Evelyn Dermer?
不知道  苏比·赛尔斯是谁
I don't know. Who's Soupy Sales?
天啊  有个很丑的裸男在拉大提琴
Oh my god, there's an unattractive nude man playing the cello.
是啊  还好他不是在玩更小的乐器
Yeah, well just be glad he's not playing a smaller instrument.
你的生活真有意思  亲爱的
You have some life here, sweetie.
我知道  妈
I know. And Mom,
我知道你跟爸很不高兴我没嫁给巴瑞
I realize you and Daddy were upset when I didn't marry Barry
住在郊外的大房子  生活无忧
and get the big house in the suburbs with all the security and everything,
可是  这样对我而言好多了
but this is just so much better for me, you know?
我知道  你不爱巴瑞  亲爱的
I do know. You didn't love Barry, honey.
我也没见过你这么快乐过
And I've never seen you this happy.
看着你  我心里在想"这正是我要的生活"
I look at you and I think, oh, this is what I want.
是为我着想吗
For...me.
不只是为你着想
Well, not just for you.
什么意思
Well, what do you mean?
我在考虑离开你爸
I'm uh, considering leaving your father.
好  这样会不会太讨巧
All right. Tell me if this is too cute.
同志婚礼  用鸡胸肉
Lesbian wedding, chicken breasts.
天啊  我快吐了
Oh god. I think I'm gonna be sick.
怎么了  我又不在上面放小乳头
Why? It's not like I'm putting little nipples on them.
-你根本不知道他们关系不好  -对
- And you had no idea they weren't getting along?- None.
他们不常吵架吗
They didn't fight a lot?
不  他们连话都不讲
No! They didn't even talk to each other.
天啊  我怎么会知道他们有矛盾
God, how was I supposed to know they were having problems?
在我那个时代  可没离婚这档子事
In my day, divorce was not an option.
看谁醒了
Hey, look who's up.
我只是无法相信会这样
I just can't believe this is happening.
我小时候每个人的父母都在闹离婚
I mean, when I was little, everybody's parents were getting divorced.
我只是觉得  我长大就不用担心这事了
I just figured as a grownup I wouldn't have to worry about this.
你能不能把她这一举动当做对你的讨好呢
Is there any chance that you can look at this as flattering?
她这样做是想向你学习
I mean, she's doing it because she wants to be more like you.
那她光学我的发型不就好了吗
Well, then, you know, couldn't she have just copied my haircut?
我父母离婚时  他们还叫我去看心理医生
You know, it's funny when my parents got divorced, they sent me to this shrink,
她告诉我  所有的小孩都会自责
and she told me that all kids have a tendency to blame themselves.
就你而言  还真是那么回事
But in your case it's actually kinda true.
就是他
That's him.
该死  我邮购的爷爷还没送到
Damn. My mail order grandfather hasn't come yet.
-菲比  -是我  你好  艾德曼先生
- Phoebe? - Yes, hi, Mr. Adelman.
幸会
Nice to see you.
幸会  谢谢你来见我
Hi. Thanks for meeting me.
没什么
Oh, that's all right,
不过你的确打扰了我忙着呆坐的一天
although you did cut into my busy day of sitting.
你要坐下来吗
Um, do you wanna sit?
不  不用了
Oh, no, please,
我早上花了好长时间才站起来
I spent most of mid-morning trying to stand up.
我能帮你什么忙  亲爱的
Now uh, what can I do for you, my dear?
是这样  我不知道该怎么开口
OK. I don't know how to say this, but
当你太太的灵魂离开她身体的时候
I think when your wife's spirit left her body,
附到了我身上
it um, kind of stuck around in me.
你说我太太在你身上
You're saying, my wife is in you?
你用不着相信我
Yeah. Ok, you don't have to believe me but
不过你能想出她有什么未完成的心愿吗
um, can you think of any unfinished business
有什么原因让她不肯离开吗
she might have had, like any reason she'd be hanging around?
我不知道该说什么  亲爱的
Well, I don't know what to tell you dear.
我唯一能够想到的是
The only thing I can think of is that
以前她常说  她死之前想见识一切
she always used to say that before she died, she wanted to see everything.
-一切吗  -一切
- Everything? - Everything.
那可真是个大工程
Whoa, that's a lot of stuff.
等等  我想起来了
Oh, wait, I remember,
她还说她想最后再跟我上一次床
she also said she wanted to sleep with me one last time.
对不起  我脑袋里有笑声
I'm sorry, there's laughing in my head.
也值得一试吧
Worth a shot, huh?
看这张
Look at this.
这是三年前万圣节的照片
These are from Halloween three years ago.
你看  这是巴瑞
Oh, look, here's Barry.
他是直接从办公室赶过来的吗
Did he have to come straight from the office?
不  那是他的万圣节装束
No, that was his costume.
他是个正牙医生  但他扮成了普通牙医
See, he's actually an orthodontist, but he came as a regular dentist.
各位
Um, you guys,
记得我以前说"谢了  我自己可以"吗
you know when I said before, "thank you, but I don't really need your help"?
事实上  我想你说的是
Actually, what I think you said was,
"别乱碰东西  滚出我的厨房"
"don't touch that, and get the hell out of my kitchen."
真的吗  真奇怪  不过
Really? Weird. Anyway,
我一切都计划得很周到  我精心计划过
see, I planned everything really well. I planned and I planned and I planned.
只是现在我实际烹饪的时间不够用
It just turns out, I don't think I planned enough time to actually do it.
-摩妮卡  要帮忙吗  -最好不过
- Hey, Mon, you want some help? - If you want.
累死了  我带她到处去逛了
What a day. I took her everywhere.
现代美术馆  洛克菲勒中心  自由女神像
The Museum of Modern Art, Rockefeller Center, Statue of Liberty.
她还缠着你吗
She's still with you?
对  我想她还没全看遍呢
Yeah. I guess she hasn't seen everything yet.
我马上回来  她必须再去一趟厕所
I'll be right back, she has to go to the bathroom again.
好漂亮的脸蛋
Oh, such a pretty face.
真有意思  就只有我们女生
This is so much fun, just the girls.
知道我们该做什么吗
You know what we should do?
-谁有大麻吗  -天啊
- Does anybody have any marijuana? - God!
听着  不准在这堆食物旁边抽大麻
All right, look, nobody's smoking pot around all this food.
没关系  我从没抽过  只想试一试
That's fine. I never did it. I just thought I might.
最近和谁上床啦
So, what's new in sex?
最近和谁上床了
What's new in sex?
我只跟你老爸做过
The only man I've ever been with is your father.
我切  我切  我什么都没听到
I'm dicing, I'm dicing, I don't hear anything.
我不是在说你爸爸不好  亲爱的
I mean, this is no offense to your dad, sweetie,
我只是在想  或许有更好的呢
but I was thinking there might be more.
对不起  你知道吗
Oh, I'm sorry. You know what?
-我没办法跟你谈这件事  -好吧  好吧
- I cannot have this conversation with you. - Alright, alright.
你甚至还没告诉我爸
I mean, god, you just come in here, and drop this bomb on me,
就到我这里来丢这颗重磅炸弹
before you even tell Daddy.
-你到底要什么  我的祝福吗  -不
- What? What do you want? Do you want my blessing? - No.
-那你要我劝你别这样吗  -不
- You want me to talk you out of it? - No.
那你要干什么
Then what. What do you want?
我以为只有你会理解我
I guess I just figured of all people you would understand.
你凭什么觉得我会理解我
Why on earth would I understand this?
你没有嫁给你的巴瑞  亲爱的
You didn't marry your Barry, honey.
但我嫁了
But I married mine.
好了  各位  我们有麻烦了
All right people, we're in trouble here.
我们只剩下12小时36分钟了
We've only got 12 hours and 36 minutes left.
快  快  快
Move, move, move!
摩妮卡  我觉得你应该加上德文字幕
Monica, I feel like you should have German subtitles.
乔伊  加快速度
Joey, speed it up!
抱歉  是猪的问题
I'm sorry, it's the pigs.
它们死活不肯进毯子
they're reluctant to get in the blankets!
摩妮卡  怎么会这么手忙脚乱
Monica, how did this happen?
我以为你全计划好了
I thought you had this all planned out.
你想让我哭吗
Do you want me to cry?
这就是你想看到的吗
Is that what you want?
你想看到我哭吗
Do you wanna see me cry?
长官  不是的  长官
Sir! No sir!
好了  你呢
All right, you!
不  听着  我说过我不参与这件事
No. Look, I told you I am not a part of this thing.
罗斯  我知道你跟卡罗尔和苏珊有过节
All right, look, Ross. I realize that you have issues with Carol and Susan,
我很同情你  真的
and I feel for you, I do.
但是如果你不帮我
But if you don't help me cook,
我会用那一堆热狗肠
I'm gonna take a bunch of those little hot dogs,
创造出一道新的开胃菜叫罗斯猪肉卷
and I'm gonna create a new appetizer called "pigs in Ross".
好  挖香瓜球
All right, ball the melon.
为什么我得切丁  他却可以挖香瓜球呢
Hey! How come I'm stuck dicing, when he gets to ball the melon.
进行得怎么样
How's it going?
非常顺利  照计划进行着
It's goin' great. Right on schedule.
还有我快乐的小帮手们
Got my little happy helpers.
好的  随便吧
That's fine, whatever.
怎么了
What's the matter?
没事  好吧  诸事不顺
Nothing. Ok, everything.
我想我们婚礼要取消了
I think we're calling off the wedding.
-什么  -你还是会付我钱的吧
- What? - You're still gonna pay me, right?
也不能太自私是吧
Or something a little less selfish.
卡罗尔  发生什么事了  怎么了
Carol, what's the matter? What happened?
-我爸妈下午来电话说他们不来了  -上帝
- My parents called this afternoon to say they weren't coming. - Oh my god.
我知道他们不赞成这件事
I mean, I knew they were having trouble with this whole thing,
可他们毕竟是我父母
but they're my parents.
他们应该把我嫁出去的
They're supposed to give me away and everything.
好的  别难过了
It's ok. I'm sorry.
然后我跟苏珊大吵了一架
And then Susan and I got in this big fight
因为我说或许应该取消婚礼
because I said maybe we should call off the wedding,
然后她说  我们结婚不是为了他们
and she said we weren't doing it for them,
而是为了我们自己
we were doing it for us,
我不认清这点的话
and if I couldn't see that,
或许我们真该取消婚礼
then maybe we should call off the wedding.
我不知道该怎么办
I don't know what to do.
不敢相信我要说这些话
I uh can't believe I'm gonna say this,
但我认为苏珊说得对
but I think Susan's right.
真的吗
You do?
你爱她吗  你不用说得太斩钉截铁
Look, do you love her? And you don't have to be too emphatic about this.
我当然爱她了
Of course I do.
那就是了
Well then that's it.
如果你父母无法接受  就让他们去吧
And if George and Adelaide can't accept that, then the hell with them.
听着  如果我的父母不让我娶你
Look, if my parents didn't want me to marry you,
那绝对阻止不了我
no way that would have stopped me.
这是你的婚礼  办吧
Look, this is your wedding. Do it.
你说得对  当然你是对的
You're right. Of course you're right.
-那我们继续吗  -继续吧
- So we're back on? - We're back on.
你们都听到了  削啊  剁啊  切啊
You heard the woman. Peel, chop, devil!
真不敢相信  我耽误了两分钟
I can't believe I lost 2 minutes.
真是巧妇难为无米之炊
It just seems so futile, you know?
这么多女人  却无法下手
All these women, and nothing.
我觉得自己像失去超能力的超人
I feel like Superman without my powers, you know?
我有披风  但是我飞不起来
I have the cape, and yet I cannot fly.
现在你理解我每天的感受了吧
Well now you understand how I feel every single day,
整个世界都是我的同志婚礼
The world is my lesbian wedding.
谁要奶油糖  没人要吗
Butterscotch? No one?
好吧  你们会后悔的
All right, you'll be sorry later.
-谢谢  -随时效劳
- Thank you. - Any time.
罗斯
Ross.
没有任何一件事比两个人
You know, nothing makes God happier than when two people,
不论性别  因爱而结合使神更快乐
any two people, come together in love.
亲朋  好友  我们今天齐聚一堂
Friends, family, we're gathered here today
见证卡罗尔和苏珊神圣的婚礼
to join Carol and Susan in holy matrimony.
老天  现在我什么都见识了
Oh my god. Now I've seen everything!
她走了  她走了 她走了
Whoa, she's gone. She's gone. She's gone!
继续  结婚吧  快  快
Go ahead, get married. Go, go.
-你看看她们  -是啊  我不禁羡慕她们
- Would you look at them? - Yeah, can't help but.
那道猪肉卷好不好吃
How's that pig-in-the-blanket workin' out for you?
对  那些捣蛋鬼是我包的
I wrapped those bad boys.
-我想念罗丝  -是吗
- I miss Rose. - Oh, yeah?
我知道这有点奇怪
I know it's kind of weird,
她曾是我生活的一大部分
but I mean, she was a big part of my life there, you know,
我现在觉得有点孤单
and now I just feel kind of alone.
我听到你刚说的话
You know, I uh, I couldn't help but overhear what you just said,
我想你也该把罗丝抛在脑后了
and I think it's time for you to forget about Rose,
继续你的生活
move on with your life...
我帮你拿杯饮料吧
how 'bout we go get you a drink?
好的  你真好
Ok, that's so nice.
我连搭讪的话都不用绞尽脑汁想了  是不是
I shouldn't even bother coming up with a line, right?
妈  好玩吗
Hey, Mom? Having fun?
当然  我刚才跟一个好高大的女人跳舞了
Oh, am I! I just danced with a wonderfully large woman.
另外有三个女孩在餐点旁对我挤眼
And three other girls made eyes at me over the buffet.
我不是说这是我所要追求的
Oh, I'm not saying it's something I wanna pursue,
但知道我选择多多  好令人欣慰
but it's nice to know I have options.
酒还有吧
There's more alcohol, right?
-你好吗  -好
- How you doin'? - Ok.
-你今天做了件好事  -是
- You did a good thing today. - Yeah.
-想跳舞吗  -不想  算了
- You wanna dance? - No, that's fine.
来吧  我让你领舞
Come on. I'll let you lead.
好
Ok.
好吧  不管直的弯的  大家都是人嘛
All right look. Penis, schmenis, okay. We're all people.
你们觉得我们之中哪一个会先结婚
Ok, which one of us do you think is gonna be the first one to get married?
摩妮卡  我已经结过婚了
Well, Mon, I was married.
我也是  严格意义上讲
Yeah, me, too, technically.
我举行过婚礼
I had a wedding.
好吧  我只是想了个好玩的话题
All right, just trying to start an interesting discussion.
我想到了  哪一个会最晚结婚
I got one. Which one of us do you think will be the last to get married?
你们说小本算不算
Isn't Ben in this?
算啊
Oh, yeah!